Guide to the Wilfrid S. Sellars Papers, 1899-1990 ASP.1991.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Roy Wood Sellars, 1909-1974; VII.
  - Manuscripts and Offprints, 1933-1973; 4.
    - "Some Theses with Respect to Relativity", 1970 (Box 195, Folder 12)
    - "A Statement of Critical Realism", 1939 (Box 195, Folder 13)
    - "Strategic Thinkers of the Present: Whitehead and Santayana", undated (Box 195, Folder 14)
    - "Suggested Outlook", 1972 (Box 195, Folder 15)
    - "Technical Specialization and Comprehensiveness in Philosophy", undated (Box 195, Folder 16)
    - "Terminal", 1973 (Box 195, Folder 17)
    - "The Texture of the New Ontology: Finding a Place for Life and Values", c. 1966-1973 (Box 195, Folder 18)
    - "Time in Frames, Time Between the Frames, and the Behavior of Light", undated (Box 195, Folder 19)
    - "'True' as Contextually Implying Correspondence", 1959 (Box 195, Folder 20)
    - "Truth as the Achievement of Knowledge", 1958-1959 (Box 195, Folder 21)
    - "Two Naturalistic Theories of Sense Perception", undated (Box 195, Folder 22)
    - "Two Semantic Blunders of Einstein", undated (Box 195, Folder 23)
    - "Undermining the Foundations", undated (Box 195, Folder 24)
    - "Valuing has Objective Import After Its Own Kind", undated (Box 195, Folder 25)
    - Fragments
      - Critical realism, undated (Box 195, Folder 26)
      - Double knowledge approach, undated (Box 195, Folder 27)
      - Miscellaneous topics, undated (Box 195, Folder 28)
      - Religion and society, undated (Box 196, Folder 1)
      - Socialism and other political systems, undated (Box 196, Folder 2)
      - Social philosophy, undated (Box 196, Folder 3)
      - Values, morals, ethics, undated (Box 196, Folder 4)
        This subseries includes manuscripts that were written by other philosophers and sent to Roy Wood Sellars for various reasons. The manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by author and known dates are supplied. A few of these manuscripts were given as compliments to RWS, since the authors discuss his work. Additional manuscripts were submitted to RWS for comment. Other authors sent RWS their manuscripts simply because they felt the subject matter might have interested RWS.
    - Campbell, Donald,"Pattern Matching as an Essential in Distal Knowing", 1964-1965 (Box 196, Folder 5)
    - Delaney, C. F.,"Recent Work on American Philosophy", 1971 (Box 196, Folder 6)
    - Hofstadter, Albert,"Aspects of Human Equality", 1955 (Box 196, Folder 7)
    - Kaufmann, Walter,"Kierkegaard: A Preliminary Expectoration", undated (Box 196, Folder 8)
    - Kovaly?, Paul,"The Philosophy of American Realism", c. 1968-1973 (Box 196, Folder 9)
    - Lorenz, Konrad,"Kant's Doctrine of the A Priori in Light of Contemporary Biology", 1962 (Box 196, Folder 10)
    - Melchert, Norman Paul,"Realism, Materialism, and the Mind: The Philosophy of Roy Wood Sellars", 1968 (Box 196, Folder 11)
    - Reck, Andrew,"The Realism of Roy Wood Sellars", 1970 (Box 196, Folder 12)
    - Sellars, Wilfrid
      - "this I or he or it (or thing) which thinks", 1970 (Box 196, Folder 13)
      - "Notes on Anselm's Ontological Argument", undated (Box 196, Folder 14)
    - Skyrms, Brian,"The Explication of 'X Knows that P'", undated (Box 196, Folder 15)
    - Warren, Preston
      - "Crossing the Philosophical Divides", 1971 (Box 196, Folder 16)
      - Roy Wood Sellars, 1972 (Box 196, Folder 17)
    - Unknown or multiple authors
      - The New Scholasticism, Roy Wood Sellars issue, 1971 (Box 196, Folder 18)
      - Project proposal for the program and its import, c. 1959-1973 (Box 196, Folder 19)